Today I find all of you here as the lights sitting before Me.
And with these lights I feel
the Deepawali really celebrated,
I see the twingling of those eyes,
twinkling in the eye
of that light which is within you.
In the lamp of light we have to put
something that is soft, like ghee,
that’s something very mild and soft,
is the love of our heart.
And that burns to give this soothing
light of love to others.
Such a person who has this light
of love, loves himself as well,
and emits love for others.
I’ve been hearing about the way people
used to torture themselves
to become saintly.
There’s no need at all for sahaja yogis
- at all - to torture themselves.
But to be the light of a higher
magnitude,
they have to be full of love.
And this love they get it
from where?
You may say it is from Me,
is true, but the sap of the tree
flows all over,
and all the tree must live
together.
Any leaf that wants to separate itself
will die out.
So is the collectivity which is going
to make you grow.
Any ideas which you have of keeping
yourself out,
or preserving yourself out, or having
your houses separate
from the collectivity, may be
dangerous.
The houses may be separate, but they
must be the houses of all the sahaja yogis.
Anybody who comes to your house,
who is a sahaja yogi,
is owner of that house.
That sort of a feeling should be
developed,
when the light you take out from
one room to another room,
it does not say: “This is my room
so I give light,
if I go to another room
I will not give light.”
Now, light is absolutely detached.
If you do not look after your light,
it will extinguish.
You have to look after it till it takes
its proper stand.
And once it takes a particular
stand,
then you are a strong sahaja
yogi.
Then they see the light
on your face.
And then you manifest light
in their lives.
This light, if you put finger on it,
it will burn.
But the light of love never
burns.
It dissolves all that is bad.
It rejects, it turns away from whatever
that is wrong.
It has patience
and it expels the darkness.
Darkness within and without.
In this Diwali day, let us wish
that so many people fall into
this ocean of joy,
and the ocean of joy has to expand
its borders.
A sea never does that,
but sahaja yogis can do it because
they have ocean of love in their hearts.
So I wish you all a very happy Diwali,
in the sense
that you will enlighten more lights,
every sahaja yogi
should enlighten at least hundred
lights in this year.
Every person you meet, you can talk
to them about Sahaja Yoga.
Not about Me. Later on,
gradually.
So I hope you’ll enjoy your Diwali here,
all of you,
and we’ll create an ocean which
will expand, grow,
and engulf more and more people
into this joyous company.
So, all these things should be attended too and you must see to it
that you keep your personality alright, your nationality alright,
your clothes alright, everything alright. But,
your personality must merge with the collective otherwise there will be a big problem.
And I respect all the people who keep their personality,
keep their nationality, keep the way they are.
Actually these days the situation is such that fashion starts
so people start cutting their hair, fashion starts, they start making their hair funny.
So, in the fashion you cannot even make out which personality one person is.
It is better to dress up in you own personality, in your own country way, the way you are.
And it is very beautiful to see diversity in that way creating a beautiful unity among us.
The personality, as it is, keep it. It’s nice.
I am happy he has shown you there are certain personalities and all that,
and when you see them you enjoy them and
everybody is enjoying their laughing at themselves.
It is a very big thing that you can laugh at yourself and appreciate it.
It is a sign of real wisdom.
On a Diwali day we have to understand that we
are all lights on the path the ascent of many people.
We all should keep our light afloat, enjoyable, laughing at ourselves,
making fun of each other, sometimes pulling legs is alright,
but in no way, in no way it should be hurting another personality,
means to say something on the physical side of it.
Specially one should not remark like somebody is a lame person or a blind person,
you should never make fun of such a thing.
Otherwise the [UNCLEAR] and behaviour is very
important to see and will be very much appreciated.
Actually I had never known so many foreigners – as I call them – they are now My children.
And when I go to different countries I see
different-different styles and different-different ways
of their food, their – every habit is different.
I really enjoy the way people eat differently and talk differently.
It’s very nice, but in all that one has to see the beauty:
how God has created so many human beings, so many faces,
by little-little small little cells how he has changed the faces of people.
Then every country has a different type of a face.
Then every – even a part of the country may have a different type of a face.
So, all this is done just to create beauty and love,
to show that even if we are all outside different inside we are one.
Animals are – all of them are – I mean there is not much of a difference.
Unless and until you are very particular you
cannot find out one animal from another animal.
If they live with human beings of course it is different, but otherwise
if you go in the jungle you cannot make out one tiger, one to another.
It is all just the same, they look the same.
But this differentiation has come in human beings.
And in Sahaja Yoga when you grow more the outside differences
could be even more interesting, could be much more interesting.
But the one sign I know about Sahaja Yogis is that their faces glow.
Faces glow, eyes have a beautiful twinkling in
the eyes and they are all, all the time enjoying.
That is what it is we have to celebrate
our own joy, our own virtue,
our own righteousness and all our styles.
May God bless you.